meditation number 17 is the mind goes
automatically to it and part of taking
refuge is to keep pictures and statues
and books around your house okay I like
Gelson's house because it's very
Buddhist house
they're everywhere under everything
there's some Buddhist thing there's
pictures everywhere there's a tsongkhapa
on the heater little so if you look
close you can see so copper he's in the
heater you know and I was like hi I can
see you you know you know there's a part
in the long room that's you know we're
need some Campion's
we don't I mean we rather go to a DCI
event then go to a temple and wave in
sense right but it's a very good custom
to keep lots of Buddha's in your house
okay so mr. woo there's no room to sit
in his house because there's all
Buddhist you know and that's a good
habit okay
Jewish people have a custom to put a
special thing at the door right
what's it calling me suta visita massive
mess suta anyway they have this thing
and I decided I want a Buddhist one so I
got a little Buddha from Sinai where
Buddha first thought you gave it to me
or no candy good no shopping you gave me
in Varanasi little Buddha who gave me
from where Buddha first taught then I
carved a hole in my near my door and I
glued it in there you know so every time
I come and go I have to see this
Buddhist looking at me you know in the
lamb it says that's a very good custom
okay why when you have trouble you will
think about Buddhist okay
so generally it's important Jewish
people have another good custom you're
not allowed to make a statue of God
right like in their temple there's no
images because they say it's impossible
to make a picture of a holy beam not
possible so you're not allowed to try
but and I used to think you know I don't
need all these Buddha's around you know
I just have to clean them right so I'm
like I don't need them I used to have
them they got dusty my mama said clean
them I say I don't want to then you know
I started I just won't have any you know
but uh what the laundry obsess about
refuge it's part of refuge to keep
Buddhist in your house okay it could be
Tara it could be check on you Jamal it
could be anything okay
but just keep them where you have to see
them I put one on the refrigerator
because that's my real alter you know
I'm always going there for refuge and
you know so I put one of those magnetic
one on the refrigerator it's always
looking at me
okay so it's a custom so the idea is and
if you have books all over your house
Buddhist books you know it's a good
tradition to keep some above your head
where you walk into your house on the
inside above the door and there's
accustomed to keep them above your head
where you sleep okay and it's a custom
not to keep them where your feet are
pointing on your bed okay so not at the
end of your bed no books or Buddha
pictures where the feet of your when you
sleep your feet are facing them put them
on the other side near your head and
maybe someplace where you can see them
when you fall asleep right so I have
some images you know in my bedroom and
there I have Tony Lamas collected works
above my head I figure that's a dusting
and then I have all the Buddhists around
that and some copy us right there okay
so it's part of going for refuge to keep
images around you all the time
because when you die it will stay in
your mind okay it will stay in your mind
when you get in a car accident when you
get cancer when you're lying on the bed
in the hospital the last time your mind
will go to that you see your mind will
go to what you saw your whole life okay
so keep lots of things around it's not a
Buddhist home decorating okay and it's
not a competition my Buddhist more
valuable than your Buddha you know mine
is silver - gold yours is just wood you
know it's not like that okay but keep
them around we have a nice image of my
teacher there Anton from Moscow may help
us to make it
and so it's nice to have your teachers
face around there's some copper over
here and there's a ton copper here and
some of my teachers are here and so
keep-keep images around keep books
around little stupas okay the pictures
to represent Buddha the books represent
Dharma sorry the stupas are Buddha mind
body mind and speech in in Tibet
language we don't say altar we say the
place where Buddhist body speech and
mind live okay so body is image speeches
you keep a book there like ting contain
and in mind is you keep a small stupid
there and then that's a good author it
has three things body speech and mind
okay so during this meditation you can
just think about part of retreat is to
make plans for after you get home okay
part of the experience of retreat is to
make plans for when you get out of
retreat okay so I when I do retreats I
keep a journal I always bring an empty
journal and maybe in the evening I sit
down with my hot chocolate and I write
if I have good ideas you know like oh I
need a Buddha over my my front door or
something like that then I make a note
because I will forget when I get on the
airplane
you know I'll forget everything so keep
a journal you shouldn't talk during
these retreats any retreat you shouldn't
talk even if you're staying with other
people try not to talk someone talks to
you just go like this okay don't talk
back all right
and it's a it helps to retrieve I didn't
I don't know many many many one months
retreats during my business career and
the first time I felt a little bit
nervous I thought oh I will
my business will get worse you know if I
go away for one month then my business
will get worse you know I was worried
about it and I waited for a long time
then I finally I did my first retreat in
a bedroom next to my Lamas Benner and I
stayed in the bedroom for one month and
some other monk brought me food and
stuff like that then when I came out I
had all these ideas about acip
to create acip to save all the books and
now it's 31 years right so you don't
waste your time in retreat okay it feels
like you are gonna get behind in your
work all the other people will get the
good position and your work will be
worse or something like that but what I
learned was all my cool ideas came
during labor during retreat one-month
retreat so I encourage you to do it and
and bring a journal with you when you do
this retreat okay don't forget okay